好的。在本次讲座中，
All right. In this lecture,
我们将学习如何使用伪类来设置超链接的样式，
we will learn how to style hyperlinks using pseudo classes,
但让我们先在这里快速修复这个红色文本
but let's start by quickly fixing this red text here
我们不想要的。
that we don't want.
实际上我在这里要做的就是把它放回去
And actually what I will do here is to put this back
对第一个孩子，
to first child,
记住这不起作用，然后我会发表评论
which remember doesn't work and then I will place a comment
这里使用命令或控制斜杠。
here using command or control slash.
然后我会简单地写下这就是误解
And then I will simply write that this is that misconception
我们在上一个视频中谈到的。
that we talked about in the last video.
所以这行不通。
So this won't work.
好的。所以有了这个，
Okay. And so with this,
我们开始稍微记录一下我们的代码。
we are starting to document our code just a little bit.
所以现在我将在这里添加另一条评论
And so now I will actually add another comment here to say
在这里，我们现在将设置链接或超链接的样式。
that here we will now be styling links or hyperlinks.
现在我们可以认为这就是我们样式链接的方式。
Now we could think that this is how we style links.
所以我们只写A。
So we just write the A.
所以选择页面上的所有锚元素
So selecting all the anchor elements on the page
然后我们可以，例如，设计他们的颜色。
and then we could, for example, style their color.
而且，让我们这么说
And, let's say that
我们想在这里使用同样的蓝色。
we wanted to go with this same blue color here.
然后当我们重新加载它实际上这个链接
And then as we reload it actually this links
看起来已经不错了。
look already nice.
所以这个变成了蓝色，而这些在下面
So this one turned blue and these ones down here and
可能还有这些。
probably also these ones.
是的，对。
Yeah, right.
然而，简单地这样做，实际上并不是一个好的做法。
However, doing simply this, is actually not a good practice.
所以我们不应该简单地选择锚并设置它的样式。
So we shouldn't simply select the anchor and style it.
相反，我们应该设置锚的伪类
Instead we should style a pseudo class of the anchor
因为这将使我们能够针对不同的状态。
because that will then allow us to target different states.
所以我们要设置样式的第一个
So the first one that we want to style
是链接伪类。
is the link pseudo class.
所以这基本上会针对所有的锚元素
So this will basically target all the anchor elements
具有 href 属性的，
that have an href attribute,
因为请记住，我们实际上可以指定锚点，
because remember that we can actually specify anchors,
所以 A 元素没有 href 属性。
so A elements without the href attribute.
因此，他们将成为我们拥有的代码的目标
And so they will then be targeted with the code that we had
之前，即使它们不是真正的链接。
before, even though they are not really a link.
但有了这个，
But with this,
所以通过指定链接伪类，
so by specifying the link pseudo class,
这将只针对实际链接。
this will then only target actual links.
因此，如果我们重新加载，它仍然看起来不错。
So if we reload, it still looks nice.
让我很快地向你展示这一点。
Let me actually show that to you very quickly.
所以在这里，如果我们不得不涂成红色，
So here, if we had to color of red,
然后如果我在这里的某个地方指定一个 A 元素，
and if I then specify an A element somewhere here,
一个测试A，所以这里的某个地方。
a test A, so that's somewhere here.
所以你会看到这个现在实际上是红色的。
And so you'll see that this one is now actually red.
这就是来自这里的这种风格，
And so that's coming from this style here,
但不是从这个。然后再次，
but not from this. And again,
那是因为这个只针对一个元素
that's because this one only targets A element that do
实际上有 href 属性，而这个没有。
actually have href attribute, which this one does not.
因此，让我们在这里摆脱它以及这条规则。
So let's get rid of it and also of this rule here.
是的，
And yeah,
所以现在你知道应该这样做了。
so now you know that this is how it should be done.
让我们在这里继续查看这些链接。
Let's actually keep looking at these links here.
现在，另一件事要做
Now, another thing that's coming to do
当我们对链接进行样式设置时，就是去掉下划线。
when we style links is to get rid of the underline.
所以这是另一个用于设置文本样式的 CSS 属性，
So here is another CSS property to style text,
这是文本装饰，
which is text-decoration,
在这种情况下，我们可以将其设置为无。
which we can set in this case to none.
但是我将向您展示许多其他值
But there are a bunch of other values that I will show you
在一秒钟内，
in a second,
但现在我们只想摆脱下划线。
but for now we just want to get rid of the underline.
所以在这些情况下，它在倍数中很常见
And so in these situations, it's very common in multiples
CSS 属性使用值为 none。
CSS properties to use the value of none.
确实没有w 没了。
And indeed now it's gone.
当然，同样的，在这里。
And the same of course, down here.
伟大的。接下来我们有访问过的伪类。
Great. Next up we have the visited pseudo class.
如此多的网站实际上以不同的方式显示链接
So many sites actually display links differently
如果他们之前被点击过。
if they have been clicked before.
一个很好的例子就是谷歌
And one good example of that is Google
在 CSS 中，这真的很容易做到。
and in CSS that would be really easy to do.
我们所要做的就是选择锚点
All we had to do was to select the anchors
与访问的伪类。
with the visited pseudo class.
所以在这里我们可以给他们一个不同的颜色。
So here we could them give them a different color.
让我们说像浅灰色，像这样的东西。
Let's say like a light gray, something like this.
好的。但在实践中，我们实际上从未这样做过。
Okay. But in practice, we never do that actually.
所以在普通页面上，
So on normal pages,
通常我们总是只给出访问过的链接，
usually we always just give the visited links,
与链接伪类上的颜色相同。
the same color as on the link pseudo class.
所以就是这样做
So that's just do that
并收工。
and call it a day.
而这两条规则现在实际上非常相似。
And these two rules are actually now very similar.
所以通常我们实际上将它们组合在一起，
And so usually we actually group them together,
但现在让我们不要那样做，好好地保持一切
but now let's not do that and keep everything just nicely
分开只是为了在这里学习。
separated just for the purpose of learning here.
不管怎样，现在让我们进入下一个关于锚点的伪类，
Anyway, let's now go to our next pseudo class for anchors,
这是我要说的最重要的一个，
which is the most important one I would say,
那就是悬停。
and that is hover.
所以在悬停伪类中，
So in the hover pseudo class,
我们可以定义我们想要应用到的任何样式
we can define any styles that we want to be applied to the
一旦元素被鼠标悬停，就锚定。
anchor as soon as the element is hovered by the mouse.
例如，假设在这种情况下，
So for example, let's say that in this situation,
我们想改变颜色
we wanted to change the color
像橙红色，
to something like orange red,
这是这些颜色名称之一
and which is one of these color names that
我其实有点喜欢。
I actually like a little bit.
然后假设我们也想改变
And then let's say that we also wanted to change
字体粗体。
the font-weight to bold.
这里有点疯狂的风格。
So kind of a bit of a crazy style here.
让我们实际上也带回下划线。
And let's actually also bring back the underline.
所以文字装饰，
So text-decoration,
而这个是这些速记属性中的另一个
and this one is another one of these shorthand properties
我们可以定义多个值。
where we can define multiple values.
所以在这种情况下，我们可以定义 text-decoration 行，
So in this case, we can define the text-decoration line,
文本装饰样式和文本装饰颜色。
text-decoration style, and text-decoration color.
我们可以说下划线，
We can say underline,
然后我们可以定义下划线的样式，
then we can define the style of the underline,
这与边框的样式非常相似。
which is very similar to the style of the border.
所以我们说点，例如，
So let's say dotted, for example,
最后是颜色。
and then finally the color.
所以说它也适用于橙红色。
So that said it also to orange red.
让我们看看当我们悬停这个链接时会发生什么
And let's see what now happens as we hover this link
它奏效了。
and it worked.
于是颜色变了，
So the color changed,
字体粗细和文本装饰也发生了变化。
the font-weight also changed and also the text-decoration.
让我们尝试另一种类似波浪的，这也很有趣。
Let's try another one like wavy, which is also fun.
然后它看起来像这样。
And then it looks like, like this.
再说一次，有点疯狂的风格。
So again, a little bit of a crazy style.
如果我们想让它不那么疯狂，
And if we want it to be a bit less crazy,
我们实际上可以省略第二个
we can actually omit the second one
然后 CSS 会自动发现
and CSS will then automatically figure out that
这里的第二个现在是颜色。
the second one here is now the color.
所以这看起来有点正常，对吧？
And so this looks a little bit more normal, right?
所以让我们保持这样。
And so let's keep it like this.
最后，
Finally,
我们还可以指定第四个伪类和
we can also specify a fourth pseudo class and
这个是活动的伪类，
this one is the active pseudo class,
这就是我们实际点击的状态。
and this is the state in which we are actually clicking.
所以当我们真的点击一个链接时，
So when we do actually click on a link,
然后伪类的行为被编辑到元素
then the act of pseudo class is edited to the element
然后我们可以像这样在这里选择它。
and we can then select that here like this.
所以就像我们对所有其他四种链接状态所做的那样，
So just like we did with all these other four link states,
所以让我们在这里继续添加一些疯狂的样式，
so let's keep adding some crazy styles here,
就像将背景颜色设置为黑色
like setting the background color to black
在那些情况下
in those situations
甚至让我们将字体样式设为斜体。
and let's even make the font style italic.
好的，就是这样。
Okay, so that's it.
所以悬停状态看起来是一样的，
So the hover state looks the same,
但现在我要点击。
but now I'm going to click.
所以这就是它的样子
And so this is what it looks like
在点击期间。
during the duration of the click.
现在，如果我搬出去放手，
Now, if I move out here and let it go,
然后它回到正常状态。
then it goes back to the normal state.
好的。
All right.
我认为实际上就是这样，
And I think that's actually it,
这里重要的是这四种状态总是
what matters here is that these four states are always
以这个确切的顺序定义。
defined in this exact order.
所以总是链接，访问，悬停和活跃。
So always link, visited, hover and active.
所以如果你更容易记住
So that is if it's easier to memorize for you
L V H A，好的。
L V H A, all right.
但当然，我们会继续这样做几次
But of course we will keep doing this a couple of more times
在接下来的课程中，
throughout the rest of the course,
然后事情对你来说会变得更容易。
and then things will become even easier for you.
现在有了这个，
And now with this,
我们实际上已经到了一些基础知识的末尾
we actually reached the end of the very basics of some
使用 CSS 的简单视觉样式。
simple visual styling with CSS.
现在当然有，
Now there is of course,
很多其他视觉的东西，比如边界收音机，阴影，
a lot of other visual stuff like border radios, shadows,
渐变、背景图像等，
gradients, background images, and more,
但我们稍后再讨论，
but we will leave that for a bit later,
但是现在我们将在这一点上留下它。
but for now we will leave it at this point.
而这已经是很大的进步。
And this is already great progress.
恭喜你走到了这一步。
So congratulations for making it this far.
并且已经学习了所有的 CSS。
And for already having learned all of the CSS.
接下来，我们将学习一些有关浏览器的知识。
Next up, we will learn something about the browser.
所以最后是一个非常有用的工具，我们当然会，
So a very helpful tool at the end, we will, of course,
通过学习一些理论和知识来继续学习 CSS 基础知识
keep learning CSS fundamentals by learning some theory and
然后学习更多的属性
then learn some more properties
与其他一些东西有关。
that are related to some other stuff.